Mindsets are attitudes and beliefs
that your brain uses as filters.
Think of them as a mental lens that impacts
how you see yourself and the world around you.
You perceive something, a conversation or an event,
and your mindset influences your thoughts and feelings
and helps you interpret them and define your choices.
More than impacting how you see, think,
and feel about things,
your mindsets ultimately drive your behavior.
For example, let's say your colleague asks you
to sketch a visual design for a brochure.
If your first thought is,
“I'm just not good at that sort of thing,”
you may be operating from a fixed mindset,
and the task at hand might make you feel
anxious or even annoyed.
It could lead you to procrastinating
and avoiding the job.
Can you think about a time
you held a fixed mindset recently?
What impact did this have on you?
The next time you find yourself
in a similar situation and mindset,
you can choose a different approach.
If you try out a growth mindset, such as
“I welcome new opportunities to grow my skills,”
you're more likely to be excited and curious
about this new challenge.
In any given moment, the mindset you operate from
can either be a deliberate choice,
or one of the many default mindsets
each of us carries.
But where do these default mindsets come from?
Typically, they are shaped by past experiences
and the reactions you've had in similar situations.
As a result, you carry helpful mindsets
and some not-so-helpful ones.
Maybe a manager in the past consistently praised you
for being an outside-the-box thinker,
so you're wired to prefer a mindset of experimentation
and risk-taking in similar environments.
Or maybe you worked at an organization where you were frequently
made to feel inadequate when you voiced suggestions during team meetings.
In turn, this instilled a mindset
that you must be an expert to speak up,
that otherwise you may look bad at your job.
Take a moment to think which mindsets you might be carrying
that are not actually serving you well.
Just because you're carrying all these
default mindsets with you,
it doesn't mean you always have to operate from them.
In fact, you can actually choose the mindset that is most appropriate at the time,
depending on what the situation is and what you want to accomplish.
Research shows it's possible if you're aware of what your current mindset is
and know which one might serve you better instead.
How important is this?
Extremely.
Mindsets can empower you or hold you back.
Study after study confirms that everything from school achievement and job performance
to life satisfaction, stress management, and even your physical health
is driven at least in part by your mindsets.
Now that you're aware of the abundance
of mindsets around you,
why not choose the ones that serve you best?